Thanks for the invite,
谢谢邀请，
so, yeah, I'm, I'm a research scientist at Google Research just across the street,
我是街对面 Google Research 的一名研究科学家，
and I want to talk today about a paper that we just put up on archives,
今天我想谈一谈我们刚刚放在存档的一篇论文，
which is a new model for
这是一种新的模型，
Text-to-image generation via Masked Generative Transformers,
通过掩码生成转换器文本到图像生成，
and as you can guess from these figures,
正如你从这些图中可以猜到的那样，
the name of the model is Muse.
这个模型的名字是 Muse 。
So this is a work that I've done with awesome set of colleagues at Google research,
这是我和谷歌研究中心的一群了不起的同事一起做的工作，
the paper and a web pages online.
一篇论文和一个在线网页。
So, many of you must be familiar with text-to-image generation,
所以，你们中的许多人一定很熟悉文本图像生成，
which has really advanced in the last year or two
它在过去一两年里确实取得了很大的进步，
and a question might be why text-to-image generation,
一个问题可能是为什么要文本图像生成，
I think it's because text is a very natural control mechanism for generation,
我认为这是因为文本是一种非常自然的生成控制机制，
we are able to express our thoughts, creative ideas through the use of text
我们能够通过使用文本来表达我们的想法和创造性的想法，
and then that allows non-experts, non-artists to generate compelling images,
允许非专家、非艺术家生成引人注目的图像，
and then be able to iterate them through editing tools
然后能够通过编辑工具重复它们，
to create your own personal art and ideas.
从而创造出你自己的个人艺术和想法。
Also, very importantly,
另外，非常重要的是，
deep learning requires lots of data
深度学习需要大量的数据，
and it is much more feasible to collect large scale paired image text data,
收集大规模的配对图文数据要可行得多，
an example is the LAION-5B dataset
一个例子是 LAION-5B 数据集，
on which models such as stable diffusion have been trained.
在这些数据集上已经训练了稳定扩散等模型。
So we should recognize that various biases exist in these datasets,
所以我们应该认识到这些数据集中存在着各种各样的偏差，
and bias mitigation is an important research problem.
而减轻偏差是一个重要的研究问题。
And lastly, these models can exploit pre-trained large language models,
最后，这些模型可以利用预先训练的大型语言模型，
which are very powerful
这些模型非常强大，
and they allow for extremely fine-grained understanding of text,
它们允许对文本进行极其细粒度的理解，
parts of speech, you know, nouns, verbs, adjectives,
词性、名词、动词、形容词，
and then be able to translate those semantic concepts to output images,
然后能够将这些语义概念转换为输出图像，
and these LLM importantly can be pre-trained on various text tasks with orders of magnitude larger text data,
这些 LLM 可以在各种具有数量级更大的文本数据的文本任务上进行预训练，
so you can pre-trained with text only data
所以你可以用纯文本数据进行预训练，
and then use paired data to do the text-to-image translation training.
然后使用配对数据来进行文本图像转换训练。
So what's the state of the art,
那么最先进的技术是什么，
you must be familiar with many of these,
你一定对其中的许多都很熟悉，
so Dall-E2 from OpenAI was one of the first models,
来自 OpenAI 的 Dall-E2 是最早的模型之一，
which is a diffusion model,
这是一个扩散模型，
that was, that was built on pre-trained CLIP representations,
这是建立在预先训练的 CLIP 表示法基础上的，
I won't have time to go into each of these terminology,
我没有时间逐一介绍这些术语，
so I'm sorry, some of you is not familiar.
所以很抱歉，对于你们中不熟悉这些的人。
Imagen from Google is also a diffusion model,
Google 的 Imagen 也是一个扩散模型，
that was built on a pre-trained large language model.
建立在预先训练好的大语言模型上。
Parti, which is another large scale model from Google,
Parti 是 Google 的另一个大规模模型，
is an autoregressive model on latent token space.
是一个基于潜在符号空间的自回归模型。
And Stable/Latent diffusion is a model release from Stability AI,
Stable/Latent 扩散是 Stability AI 发布的模型，
which is a diffusion model on latent embeddings.
它是关于潜在嵌入的扩散模型。
So, so here's an example,
这里有一个例子，
that is showing comparing DALL·E 2, Imagen and the Muse model on this particular text prompt.
显示了在这个特定的文本提示下 DALL·E 2, Imagen 和 Muse 模型的比较，
and I'll go revisit this example
稍后我将重温这个例子，
and point out some pros and cons of the different models later.
并指出不同模型的一些优缺点。
Some image editing applications that have been built on these models,
一些图像编辑应用程序基于这些模型构建的，
one example is Personalization via a tool called Dreambooth,
一个例子是 Personalization 通过一个名为 Dreambooth 的工具，
which was a paper written by some of my colleagues,
这是我的一些同事写的一篇论文，
so here the idea is that,
所以这里的想法是，
instead of generating, for example, an image of a cat,
不是生成例如一只猫的图像，
you can generate an image of your cat
而是生成一张你的猫的图片，
by fine tuning the model on some images of your own cat
通过在你自己的猫的一些图像上微调模型，
and then doing text guided generation of your cat.
然后在文本指导下生成你的猫的图像。
So that's actually proven, extremely popular,
这实际上是被证明非常受欢迎，
a couple of apps built on the Dreambooth tool have gone to the top of the App Store,
几款基于 Dreambooth 工具构建的应用程序已经登上了 App Store 的榜首，
and many people have used it to generate their own avatars for you on social media.
许多人用它生成社交媒体上自己的头像。
Another example is fine-tuning for instruction following,
另一个例子是对指令跟随进行微调，
so that one can do various kinds of flexible mask free editing,
以便可以进行各种灵活的[自由掩码]编辑，
for example, here on this top right image,
例如，在这张右上角的图像上，
we say add fireworks to the sky
我们说向天空添加烟花，
and then the model has, after fine-tuning,
然后模型经过微调，
has an understanding of concepts such as the sky and fireworks,
对天空和烟花等概念有了理解，
and it's able to do a reasonably good job of following the instruction.
它能够很好地遵循指令。
So, how is Muse different from the the prior models that I listed.
所以， Muse 和我之前列出的模型有什么不同。
So firstly, it's neither a diffusion model nor is it autoregressive,
首先，它既不是扩散模型，也不是自回归模型，
although it has some connections to both diffusion and autoregressive family of models.
虽然它与扩散和自回归模型族都有一些联系。
It is extremely fast,
它的速度非常快，
so for example a 512x512 image is generated in 1.3 seconds,
例如，一个 512x512 的图像在 1.3 秒内生成，
instead of 10s seconds for Imagen or Parti
而不是 Imagen 或 Parti 的 10 秒，
and about 4 seconds for Stable Diffusion
或者 Stable Diffusion 的大约 4 秒，
on the same hardware.
在相同的硬件上。
And on Quantitative Eval, such as CLIP score and FID,
还有在定量评估上，比如 SLIP score 和 FID ，
which are measures of how well the text prompt and the image line up with each other,
它们是衡量文本提示和图像彼此对齐程度的指标，
that's the CLIP score,
这就是 CLIP score ，
and FID is a measure of the image quality itself, the diversity and fidelity,
而 FID 是衡量图像质量本身，多样性和保真度，
the model performs very well.
这个模型表现得很好。
So, so it has similar semantic performance and quality as these much larger models,
所以它的语义性能和质量与这些更大的模型相似，
but significantly faster inference,
但推理速度要快得多，
and it has significantly better performance than Stable Diffusion.
而且它的性能明显好于 Stable Diffusion 。
All of these statements just hold true at this point in time,
所有这些说法在这个时间点上是正确的，
all of these models keep improving,
所有这些模式都在不断改进，
So there could be a new model that does even better, you know, next week.
所以，下周可能会有一款表现更好的新模型。
And some applications that are enabled by the way we train the model are Zero-shot editing,
我们训练模型的方式支持的一些应用程序是 Zero-shot 编辑，
so I'll show some examples of that Mask-free editing in painting
我将展示一些绘画中无掩码编辑的例子，
to remove objects and cropping to expand beyond the boundaries of an image.
以移除对象和裁剪扩展图像边界。
So I give a quick overview of the architecture here
我在这里先简要概述一下体系结构，
and then go into the individual components one by one.
然后再一个接一个地介绍各个组件。
Muse is mostly a transformer based architecture,
Muse 主要是一个基于转换器的架构，
for both the text and image parts of the network,
对于网络的文本和图像部分，
but we also use CNNs,
但我们也使用 CNN ，
and we also use vector quantization
我们也用矢量量化，
and we also use GANs,
我们也使用 GAN ，
so we're using a lot of the toolkits in the modern CNN,
所以我们使用了现代 CNN 的很多工具包，
modern deep network, you know, from the toolbox.
现代深度网络，使用了很多工具包。
We use image tokens, that are in the quantized latent space of a CNN-VQGAN.
我们使用了图像标记，在 CNN-VQGAN 的量化潜在空间中。
And we train it with a masking loss,
我们用掩蔽损失来训练它，
which is similar to the masking loss used in large language model,
这类似于大型语言模型中使用的掩蔽损失，
so the model is basically learning how to reconstruct mask tokens,
所以，模型基本上是在学习如何重建掩码 token ，
you pass in a set of tokens,
你传入一组 token ，
mask a bunch of them at random,
随机掩蔽其中的一组，
and then learn to predict that,
然后学习预测，
and just by doing that with variable masking ratios
通过使用可变的掩蔽率来实现，
enables it to get very good quality generation.
它就可以获得非常高质量的生成。
We have two models,
我们有两个模型，
a base model that generates 256x256 size images
一个基本模型可以生成 256x256 大小的图像，
and then a super resolution model that upscales that to 512x512.
然后一个超分辨率模型将其放大到 512x512 。
Okay, so the first major component is
好的，所以第一个主要的组成部分是，
this pre-trained large language model.
这个预先训练好的大语言模型。
So we use a language model train at Google called the T5-XXL model,
所以我们使用了谷歌的一个语言模型训练叫做 T5-XXL 模型，
which has about 5 billion parameters,
它有大约 50 亿个参数，
which was trained on many text tasks,
在许多文本任务上进行了训练，
text-to-text tasks,
文本到文本的任务，
such as translation, question answering and classification.
比如翻译，问题回答和分类。
And when a text prompt is provided,
当提供文本提示时，
it's passed in through the text encoder
它通过文本编码器传递进来，
and we get a sequence of vectors of dimens 4096,
我们得到一个维度为 4096 的向量序列，
which are then projected down to another lower dimensional sequence
然后向下投影到另一个较低维度的序列，
and those set of text tokens are then passed into the rest of the network,
然后将这些文本 token 传递到网络的其余部分，
and then we use cross-attention from the text to the image tokens to guide the generation process.
然后，我们使用从文本到图像 token 的 cross-attention 来指导生成过程。
The next component is the vector quantized latent space,
下一个组件是向量量化潜在空间，
so for this, we built first a VQ GAN,
为此，我们首先建立了一个 VQ GAN ，
which is simply a form of autoencoder
这只是一种形式的自编码器，
with some vector quantization built into the latent space.
在潜在空间中内置了一些向量量化。
And the reason we use a quantized set of tokens about,
我们之所以使用一组量化的 token ，
in most of the models we use 8000 tokens, 8192,
在大多数模型中，我们使用 8000 个 token ， 8192 ，
is that this is amenable to a cross-entropy classification type loss,
这是服从于一个交叉熵分类型损失，
so when you want to predict what token is missing,
所以，当你想要预测丢失哪个 token ，
you just say which of the 8192 tokens does it need to be
你只需说需要是 8192 个 token 的哪一个，
and that's a classification loss,
这就是分类损失，
and we find that this works much more effectively than a regression loss,
我们发现，这比回归损失要有效得多，
where you might try to predict the exact pixel values of the missing token.
在那里，你可能尝试预测丢失 token 的准确像素值。
The VQGAN has an entirely convolutional structure and encoder decoder structure,
VQGAN 具有完全卷积结构和编解码器结构，
which we found performs better than either transformer based VQGANs
我们发现比基于 transformer 的 VQGAN 性能更好，
or hybrid approaches that mix transformers and CNN.
或者 transformer 和 CNN 的混合方法。
We use a down sampling ratio of 16,
我们使用 16 的下采样率，
which generates latent,
这会产生潜在，
so, so when you go through the encoder layers of the CNN,
所以，当你到 CNN 的编码层时，
you get a latents that are of size 16 by 16
你会得到一个大小为 16x16 的潜在（空间），
from a 256 by 256 input.
从 256x256 的输入。
And the super resolution model uses another VQGAN,
而超分辨率模型使用了另一个 VQGAN ，
with latents of size 64 by 64,
潜在空间是 64x64 ，
so those are larger latents,
所以这些是更大的潜在空间，
because we want more information in each of those super resolution latents.
因为我们想要在每个超分辨率潜在空间中获得更多的信息。
And this, the VQGAN is built on work from some, from, from this paper called MaskGIT,
VQGAN 是建立在这篇论文 MaskGIT 之上的，
which is also from our group.
也是来自我们的团队。
So a key component of our masking of our training is this idea of variable ratio masking.
所以，我们训练一个关键组成部分是可变比率掩码的想法。
So given a set of tokens,
所以，给定一组 token ，
you have an image,
你就有了一个图像，
it goes through the VQ tokenizer
它经过 VQ tokenizer ，
and then you get a sequence of, say 196 tokens,
然后你得到一个序列，比方说 196 个 token ，
what we do is to drop a variable fraction of those tokens,
我们所做的是丢弃这些 token 中的一部分，
then pass into the network to learn to predict.
然后传递到网络进行学习预测。
So unlike LLMs,
所以与 LLM 不同，
where usually have a fixed ratio of tokens that's dropped,
它通常有固定的 token 投放比例，
here we use a variable distribution,
我们使用一个变量分布，
which is biased towards a very high value of
它偏向于非常高的值，
about 64% of the tokens being dropped,
大约 64% 的 token 投放，
and we find that this makes the network much more amenable to editing applications,
我们发现，这使得该网络更容易接受编辑应用程序，
like in painting and on cropping,
比如绘画和裁剪，
and since it's variable at, at inference time,
因为它在推理时间上是可变的，
you can then pass in masks of different sizes,
你可以传递不同大小的掩码，
and since it has done that during training,
因为它在训练期间这样做，
it's able to do that during inference time.
所以它能够在推理时间这样做。
Okay, so here's the base model,
好的，这是基本模型，
which has, which is producing 256x256 size images.
它产生 256x256 大小的图像。
So this is a transformer based model, the the base transformer,
这是一个基于 transformer 的模型，
that gets in the mask tokens and also the token, the text tokens,
获取掩码 token ，以及文本 token ，
so these these mask tokens are the image tokens
这些掩码令牌是图像 token ，
and then we have the text tokens,
然后是文本 token ，
so we have cross attention from the text tokens to image
所以，我们有从文本 token 到图像符号的交叉注意，
and also self attention between the image tokens,
也有图像 token 之间的自我注意，
during training, all the tokens are predicted in parallel with the cross-entropy loss,
在训练期间，与交叉熵损失并行地预测所有 token ，
but during inference, we find that it is better to do an iterative schedule,
但在推断期间，我们发现更好的做法是进行迭代调度，
where we predict a subset of the tokens first,
其中我们首先预测 token 的子集，
we choose, we choose tokens with the highest confidence,
我们选择具有最高置信度的 token ，
pass those back in as unmasked tokens,
将那些作为未屏蔽的 token 传回，
and repeat this process ah for about 12 24 steps
并且重复该过程约 12 24 次，
until all of the tokens are unmasked.
直到所有 token 都被解除屏蔽。
We find that this significantly increases the quality of the result.
我们发现，这显著提高了结果的质量。
And then the super resolution model,
然后超分辨率模型，
up samples the 256x256 image to 512x512,
向上采样 256x256 到 512x512 的图像，
importantly, this does this in token space
重要的是，这是在 token 空间中完成的，
by transforming the latent from 16x16 to 64x64.
通过将隐空间从 16x16 转换到 64x64 。
And we use cross-attention from the text embedding as well as the low-res tokens
我们使用来自文本嵌入的交叉注意以及低分辨率 token ，
and pass it into the high-res transformer.
并将其传递到高分辨率 transformer 。
So that's we mask the high-res tokens,
这是我们掩蔽高分辨率 token ，
but the low-res are left unmasked,
但低分辨率 token 不被掩蔽，
the text embedding is left unmasked,
文本嵌入不被掩蔽，
and the super-res model is trained to predict the masked higher tokens.
超分辨率模型被训练来预测被掩蔽的高 token 。
So you can see the effect here, especially on the text,
所以你可以在这里看到效果，特别是在文本上，
the the the low-res output of 256x256,
低分辨率输出是 256x256 ，
it is hard to see the text
很难看到文本，
and then once it's corrected in token space,
然后一旦在 token 空间中[更正]，
you can you can read the text,
你就可以阅读文本，
the facial features of the hamster are much more clear,
仓鼠的面部特征要清晰得多，
many details are reconstructed in token space.
许多细节都在 token 空间中重构。
What we found is that,
我们发现的是，
a cascade of models is actually very important,
一连串的模式其实是非常重要的，
if you directly try to train a 512 model,
如果你直接尝试训练一个 512x512 的模型，
it tends to, the model tends to focus too much on the details,
模型倾向于过于关注细节，
whereas if you first train a low-res model,
而如果你首先训练一个低分辨率的模型，
you get the overall semantics or the layout of the scene, right,
你会得到场景的整体语义或布局，
somewhat like what an artist might do,
有点像一个艺术家可能会做的事情，
where you you get the scene right first
你首先把场景弄对，
and then start filling in the details.
然后开始填充细节。
So one of the things we are looking at is how to,
那么我们研究的事情之一就是如何，
maybe increase the depth of this cascade,
可能增加这个[瀑布]的深度，
go from 128 to 256 to 512,
从 128 到 256 到 512 ，
see if that improves further the quality.
看看这是否会进一步提高质量。
So here you can see,
所以你可以在这里看到，
so, so here's a comparison of our token-based super resolution
所以，这是我们基于 token 的超分辨率
comparing to a diffusion based pixel-based super resolution.
与基于扩散的基于像素的超分辨率的比较。
So, here on the left,
所以，在左边，
the, the text prompt here is a rabbit playing the violin
文本提示符是一只拉小提琴的兔子，
and this is the two, these are two samples from the model of 256x256 resolution,
这是两个样本，来自 256x256 分辨率的模型，
and on the top right is the result of our token-based super resolution output,
右上角是基于 token 的超分辨率输出的结果，
so you can see that the musical notes, the details on the violin,
所以你可以看到音符，小提琴上的细节，
all of these are much more clear,
所有这些都要清晰得多，
but if we just took this and did a diffusion based super resolution,
但如果我们只是用这个，来做一个基于扩散的超分辨率，
which is just pixel hallucination, that doesn't look so good,
这只是像素[幻觉]，看起来就不那么好了，
so our token super resolution plays well with our token based approach.
所以，我们的 token 超分辨率与基于 token 的方法配合得很好。
So another important kind of heuristic or a trick is
另一种重要的启发式或技巧是
something called classifier-free guidance,
所谓的无分类器指导，
which we found is crucial at inference time
我们发现这在推理时至关重要，
to trade off diversity and quality,
以权衡多样性和质量，
what this this trick does is to simply trade off,
这个技巧所做的是简单地权衡，
sorry, push the log away from unconditional generation and towards text conditional generation,
抱歉，将日志从无条件生成推向文本条件生成，
so you can think of the scale as the amount by which you are pushing away from unconditional generation.
这样你可以将比例视为[推离]无条件生成的量。
And here's a comparison,
这是一个对比，
the image on the left, the two images on the left were generated by with the guidance scale of 0.5,
左侧的两个图像是由指导比例为 0.5 生成的，
so there's more diversity in the poses of the cat and the backgrounds,
所以猫的姿势和背景有更多的多样性，
but it's, it's now as there are more errors,
但它有更多的错误，
for example here on the mouth of the cat,
例如在猫的嘴巴上，
compared to the two images on the right,
与右侧的两幅图像相比，
which are generated with a much larger guidance scale.
这两幅图像的指导比例要大得多。
So during training,
所以在训练期间，
we just dropped some tokens with a probability of 10%,
我们以 10% 的概率丢掉一些 token ，
I'm sorry we drop conditioning with a probability of 10%,
抱歉，我们以 10% 的概率丢掉[训练]，
but then at inference time we choose a particular guidance scale.
但在推断时，我们选择了一个特定的指导标度。
Another trick,
另一个技巧，
so many tricks here to make the images look good is something called negative prompting,
这里有很多让图像看起来很好的技巧是一种叫做负面提示的东西，
so the idea here is that,
所以这里的想法是，
there are concepts which one cannot say in the text prompt itself,
有一些概念是我们不能在文本提示本身中说出来的，
for example, if you would like to generate an image,
例如，如果你想要生成一个图像，
but not have trees in it,
但其中没有树，
it's somewhat cumbersome to say that in the text prompt,
那么在文本提示中这样说就有点麻烦了，
so, so the classifier free guidance allows us to say
所以无分类器指导允许我们说，
generate this scene, but don't have trees in it,
生成这个场景，但其中没有树，
and we do that by pushing away from the negative prompt.
我们通过负面提示来做到这一点。
So here's an example,
这里有一个例子，
it text, the text prompt says cyberpunk forest by Salvador Dali,
文本提示说 Salvador Dali 的赛博朋克森林，
so that generated,
所以这就产生了，
these are two examples that were generated using that prompt,
这是使用该提示生成的两个示例，
and then I added a negative prompt,
然后我添加了一个负面提示，
where I said I don't want trees,
我说我不想要树，
I don't want green and blurry,
我不想要绿色和模糊，
that the text prompt that I provided
这是我提供的文本提示，
and then it generates these other kinds of styles,
然后它会生成其他类型的样式，
which seem to respect the negative prompt.
似乎遵守负面提示。
So that is a very useful trick,
所以这是一个非常有用的技巧，
for generating images closer to the things you're thinking of in your head.
用来生成更接近你脑海中所想的图像。
This is,
这是，
yeah, so this is the iterative decoding I mentioned earlier at inference time,
这是我之前在推理时提到的迭代解码，
and you can see that,
而且你可以看到，
decoding tokens in multiple steps is very helpful for high quality generation,
多步解码 token 对于高质量的生成非常有帮助，
so here's a sequence of unmasking steps,
所以，这有一系列的[去屏蔽]步骤，
which are generating tokens up to 18 steps
它们生成高达 18 个步骤的 token ，
and there's steady improvement in the quality of the output,
并且输出质量有了稳步的提高，
our base model uses 24 steps
我们的基本模式使用 24 个步骤，
and the super resolution model uses 8 steps,
超分辨率模式使用 8 个步骤，
but these number of steps are significantly lower
但这些步骤的数量明显低于
than the fifty or thousand steps that are required by diffusion models,
扩散模型所需的 50 或 1000 个步骤，
and this is actually one of the most important reasons for the speed of our approach,
这就是我们方法速度最重要的原因之一，
so we get like a 10x lower number of forward props,
所以我们需要的向前模型数量减少了十分之一，
that we need to push through the model.
我们需要通过模型。
However these days there's these ideas of progressive distillation,
然而，现在有一些渐进[净化]的想法，
which can potentially reduce the number of steps for diffusion models,
它可能会减少扩散模型的步骤，
and we hope to exploit that to further reduce our sampling steps,
我们希望利用它来进一步减少我们的采样步骤，
Okay, so we did some,
好的，我们做了一些，
so now on to evals that,
所以现在来评估一下，
that was a quick tour of the entire model.
这是对整个模型的快速浏览。
So we did some qualitative evals,
所以，我们做了一些定性的评估，
where we took a set of 1650 prompts from the [] paper
我们从[]论文中提取了 1650 条提示，
and generated images from our model and the stable diffusion model
从我们的模型和稳定扩散模型生成了图像，
and sent it to raters to answer the question,
并将其发送给评分员来回答问题，
which of the two images,
这两张图像中，
one from our model,
一张来自我们的模型，
one from stable diffusion,
一张来自稳定扩散，
which of them matches the prompt better.
哪一张更符合提示。
So the raters preferred our model 70% of the time,
评分者在 70% 的时间里喜欢我们的模型，
compared to 25% of the time for stable diffusion,
相比之下， 25% 的时间是稳定扩散的，
and for the remaining few percent they were indifferent,
剩下的几个百分点它们不感兴趣，
so we removed those from this plot.
所以我们把它们从这块移走了。
We also did some qualitative eval on various properties of the model,
我们还对模型的各种性质做了一些定性的评价，
how well does it respect things like cardinality.
它在多大程度上尊重基数之类的东西。
So, so here it's about, you know, counting,
所以，所以这里是关于计数，
so we have three elephants standing on top of each other,
所以我们有三头大象站在一起，
we get three elephants,
我们有三只大象，
four wine bottles, one, two, three, four,
四个酒瓶，一，二，三，四，
a tiny football in front of three yellow tennis balls,
一个小足球在三个黄色网球前，
so, seems to respect all of those,
所以，似乎遵守所有这些，
however, when the count goes up beyond six or seven,
然而，当计数超过 6 或 7 个时，
the model tends to start making mistakes.
模型往往会开始出错。
Here we are looking at different styles,
这里我们看到不同的风格，
so here's a portrait of a well-dressed raccoon,
这是一幅衣着考究的浣熊的肖像，
oil painting in the style of Rembrandt,
伦勃朗风格的油画，
pop art style and a Chinese ink and wash painting style.
波普艺术风格和中国水墨画风格。
Other evals are about composition, geometric composition,
其他的评估是关于几何构图，
three small yellow boxes on a large blue box,
三个小黄盒在一个大蓝盒上，
and a large present with a red ribbon to the left of a Christmas tree,
一个有红丝带的大礼物在圣诞树左边，
etc.
等等。
We find that it,
我们发现，
if you have want to render text,
如果你想要渲染文本，
then it does a reasonable job,
那么它就做得很好，
if there is not too many words in the text of one word or two words,
如果一个词或两个词的文本中没有太多的词，
the model is able to render them well.
模型能够很好地呈现它们。
And we are also able to provide very long, detailed prompts,
我们还可以提供非常长的、详细的提示，
so here's an example,
这里有一个例子，
an art gallery displaying monet paintings,
一个展示莫奈画作的美术馆，
the art gallery is flooded,
美术馆被淹了，
robots are going around the art gallery using paddle boards.
机器人正在使用划桨板在美术馆里转悠。
So a lot of this power comes from the language model itself,
这种力量很大程度上来自语言模型本身，
which is really, really powerful
它非常非常强大，
and able to represent each of those concepts in the embedding space,
能够在[嵌入]空间中表示这些概念中的每一个，
and what we are able to do is to map that to pixels.
我们所能做的就是将其映射到像素。
It's still mind blowing,
这仍然令人惊叹，
though it's still amazing,
这仍然是令人惊讶的，
that we can get these kinds of outputs from text prompts.
我们可以从文本提示中获得这样的输出，
Here are some failure cases, like I mentioned,
这里有一些失败的案例，就像我提到的那样，
here we asked the model to render a long number of words
这里我们要求模型呈现很长的单词，
and it did not do such a good job,
但它做得不是很好，
ten wine bottles and it stopped at one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
十个酒瓶，它停在一，二，三，四，五，六，七，
and so on.
诸若此类。
Here's a subjective comparison to other state of the art models,
这是与其他最先进模型的主观比较，
so one thing to say is that,
所以可以说一件事是，
in this case, the evaluations are, in my opinion, not very robust,
在这种情况下，在我看来，评估并不是很可靠，
because by definition,
因为根据定义，
often the text prompts and the styles we ask for are not natural,
我们要求的文本提示和样式通常不是自然的，
we want various mix and match of styles,
我们想要各种款式的混合搭配，
and so an important open research question in my mind is,
因此，在我看来，一个重要的开放研究问题是，
how do you evaluate that model a is better than model b,
你如何评价模型 a 比模型 b 更好，
other than just looking at some results,
除了只看一些结果，
I think that, that's a very interesting and open question.
我想这是一个非常有趣和开放的问题。
So here,
所以在这里，
so here I'll just point out a couple of things with the example at the bottom,
所以在这里，我通过底部的例子指出一些事情，
which is a rainbow colored penguin,
这是一只彩虹色的企鹅，
and DALL-E 2 is generating penguins,
DALL-E 2 在生成企鹅，
but doesn't do such a good job with the colors,
但在颜色方面做得不是很好，
whereas the Imagen and MUSE models seem to be able to respect []
而 Imagen 和 MUSE 模型似乎能够遵守[]，
and we think this is probably because the,
我们认为这可能是因为，
DALL-E 2 model is relying on a CLIP embedding,
DALL-E 2 模型依靠的是 CLIP embedding ，
which might lose some of these details.
这可能会丢失一些细节。
We did some quantitative eval on the metrics that we have,
我们对我们已有的指标做了一些量化评估，
which is FID and CLIP,
也就是 FID 和 CLIP ，
on a dataset called CC3M,
在一个名为 CC3M 的数据集上，
and compared to a number of other models,
并与其他一些模型进行了比较，
both in diffusion and autoregressive type models.
包括扩散模型和自回归模型。
Here for FID, score lower is better
对于 FID ，分数越低越好，
and for CLIP, higher is better.
对于 CLIP ，分数越高越好。
So, overall,
所以，总体而言，
we seem to be scoring the best on both of these metrics.
我们似乎在这两个指标上都取得了最好的成绩。
And here's the eval on COCO,
这是在 COCO 上的评估，
comparing to many of the state of the art models,
与许多最先进的模式比较，
like DALL-E, DALL-E 2, Imagen Parti,
比如 DALL-E, DALL-E 2, Imagen, Parti ，
we are almost as good as the Parti-20B model,
我们几乎与 Parti-20B 模型是一样好的，
just slightly worse in FID score,
只是在 FID 得分上略差一些，
but doing significantly better on CLIP score,
但在 CLIP 得分上要好得多，
so, so that's good,
所以，这很好，
which means that we are able to respect the semantics of the text prompt,
这意味着我们能够尊重文本提示符的语义，
better than those models,
比那些模型要好，
if one was to believe the CLIP's code.
如果你相信 CLIP 的评分的话。
And finally, runtime on TPU-v4 hardware,
最后，在 TPU-v4 硬件运行时上，
where here's the model,
这里是模型，
the resolution that is generated and the time, clock time, that it took,
生成的分辨率和所用的时钟时间，
so most of the compute goes into the super resolution,
大部分计算都是在超分辨率下进行的，
the base model takes 0.5 seconds
基础模型需要 0.5 秒，
and then it takes another 0.8 seconds to do the super resolution
然后它需要 0.8 秒来做超分辨率，
for a total of 1.3 seconds.
总共 1.3 秒。
So now here are some examples of the editing that enabled by the model,
这里有一些由模型启用的编辑示例，
on the left is a real input image,
左边是一张真实的输入图像，
and we've drawn a mask over one part of the image
我们在图像的一部分绘制了一个蒙版，
and then ask the model to fill that in with a text guided prompt,
然后要求模型使用文本指导提示来填充它，
so a funny big inflatable yellow duck,
一只有趣的充气黄色大鸭子，
hot air balloons
热气球
and futuristic, streamlined modern building.
和未来主义、流线型的现代建筑。
So all that came just zero-shot,
所有这些都是零次学习的，
we didn't do any fine tuning of the model,
我们没有对模型进行任何微调，
but the fact that we trained with variable masking
但我们使用变量掩码进行训练
allows it to do this out of the box.
允许它开箱即用地进行调整。
So another example where we do outpainting,
这是另一个我们扩图的例子，
so the mask here is the rest,
所以这里的遮罩是剩下的，
we only want to keep the, this person
我们只想保留这个人，
and replace the rest of the image,
把图像的其余部分替换掉，
and the text guided prompt was provided to fill in the rest of the region,
提供了文本引导提示，以填充该区域的其余部分，
so the London skyline,
伦敦的天际线，
a wildflower bloom at Mountain Rainier,
一朵野花盛开在雷尼尔山，
on the ring of Saturn.
在土星环上。
We can also do other kinds of editing,
我们还可以做其他的编辑，
where we took a real image with,
我们在那里拍了一张真实的照片，
there was a negative prompt use,
有一个消极的提示，
a man wearing a t-shirt
一个穿着 T 恤的人，
and then these were the positive prompts,
然后这些是积极的提示，
to, to do various kinds of style transfer,
做各种款式的转换，
on the, on the, on the t-shirt.
在 T 恤上。
And here are some examples of mask-free editing,
这里有一些无遮罩编辑的例子，
where on the top row are input images,
上面一行是输入图像，
and on the bottom, the transformed outputs,
底部是转换后的输出，
where it just relies on the text and attention between the text and images
它只依赖于文本和文本与图像之间的注意力，
to make various changes.
来进行各种更改。
So for, for example here,
所以，比如说，
we say a Shiba Inu
我们说一只柴犬，
and that, the model converts the cat to a Shiba Inu dog,
这个模型把猫变成柴犬，
a dog holding a football in his mouth,
一只狗嘴里叼着一只橄榄球球，
so here the dog itself changes,
所以这里，狗本身发生了变化，
and then this ball changes to a football,
然后，这个球变成了橄榄球，
a basket of oranges,
一篮子橙子，
where the model is able to keep the general composition of the scene
模型能够保持场景的大体构图，
and just change the apples to oranges,
只需将苹果更改为橙子，
the basket texture has also changed a little bit,
篮子的材质也有了一些变化，
but mostly the composition is kept similar.
但大部分成分都保持不变。
Here, it's able to change this,
在这里，它能够改变，
just make the cat yawning without changing the composition of the scene.
只需让猫打哈欠，而不改变场景的组成。
And one of the things we are exploring is
我们正在探索的一件事是，
how we can have further control of the model,
如何进一步控制模型，
you know, really be able to adjust specific parts of the image without affecting the rest.
能够在不影响其余部分的情况下调整图像的特定部分。
Yeah, and here's an example of iterative editing,
是的，这是一个迭代编辑的例子，
where the, the image at the top was provided and the top right,
上面和右上角提供了图像，
and then on the bottom right is the output
然后在右下角是输出，
for a croissant next to a latte with a flower latte art.
一个牛角包，旁边是一杯带有花朵艺术的拿铁。
And these are,
这些是，
we, we ran the editing for a hundred steps,
我们进行了一百个步骤的编辑，
progressively adjusting the tokens,
逐步调整 token ，
and these are the results of the different iterations of, of train of inference,
这些是推理序列的不同迭代的结果，
so you can see that,
所以你可以看到，
it starts with the cake and the latte
它从蛋糕和拿铁开始，
and then progressively transforms the cake to something that looks in between the cake and the croissant,
然后逐渐将蛋糕转变为介于蛋糕和牛角面包之间的东西，
and then finally, it looks like the croissant,
最后，它看起来像牛角包，
and similarly, the latte art changes from a heart to a flower,
同样，拿铁的艺术也从一颗心变成了一朵花，
you know, kind of some kind of an interpolation in some latent space.
有点某种潜在空间中的一种[插补]。
So because of the speed of the model,
所以，由于模型的速度，
there's some possibility of interactive editing,
这里存在一些交互编辑的可能性，
so I'll just play this short clip,
所以我将播放这个短片，
which shows how we might be able to do interactive work with the model.
展示了我们如何能够与模型进行交互工作。
So that's a real time,
所以这是真实的时间，
as in it's not sped up or slowed down,
也就是说，它没有加速或减速，
it's not perfect, but you can see the idea.
这不是完美的，但你可以看到这个想法。
So, next steps for us are improving the resolution quality,
对于我们来说，下一步是提高分辨率质量，
handling of details such as rendered text,
处理细节，如渲染文本，
probing the cross attention between text and images to enable more control,
探测文本和图像之间的交叉关注以实现更多控制，
exploring applications.
探索应用程序。
So, yeah, the paper and webpage are listed here
所以，是的，论文和网页在这里列出，
and I'm happy to take questions.
我很乐意回答问题。
Excellent, thank you so much,
太好了，非常感谢，
maybe I have one question just to get things started,
也许我有一个问题，只是为了让事情开始，
I'm curious in your opinion, what are the most important contributions that MUSE made,
我很好奇，在你看来，什么是 MUSE 做出的最重要的贡献，
specifically to achieve the very impressive speed up results,
特别是实现令人印象深刻的加速结果，
because in comparison to the past methods,
因为与过去的方法相比，
it's really like a huge gap,
这真的是一个巨大的差距，
so I'm curious,
所以我很好奇，
what like what across the many contributions like to that in your opinion.
在你看来，在众多的贡献中，这是什么样子的。
Yeah, it was primarily the parallel decoding,
是的，主要是并行解码，
so in autoregress models,
所以在自回归模型中，
by definition, you decode one token at a time,
根据定义，你一次只能解码一个 token ，
so you have to go,
所以你必须，
let's say the image consists of 196 tokens,
让我们假设图像由 196 个 token 组成，
then you're doing 196 steps,
然后，你将执行 196 个步骤，
because you unmask one token,
因为你要取消屏蔽一个 token ，
pass it back in number two, and so on,
将其传递回第二个，依此类推，
in diffusion models, what you have to do is to denoising step by step,
在扩散模型中，你要做的是一步一步地消除噪声，
yeah, you start with pure noise,
是的，你从纯噪音开始，
pass it through the network, get something out,
通过网络传递，得到一些东西，
then pass it back in and repeat this process,
然后把它传递回来，重复这个过程，
and that process needs to be fairly slow,
而这一过程需要相当缓慢，
otherwise, it breaks down,
否则，它就会崩溃，
and a lot of the research is about how to speed that up,
很多研究都是关于如何加快这一进程的，
so that takes thousands of steps,
所以，这需要成千上万的步骤，
so if you have a comparable model,
所以，如果你有一个类似的模型，
there's just a fundamental number of forward props that need to be done,
只需要做一些基本的向前[]，
so what we did instead was to go for parallel decoding,
所以，我们所做的是进行并行解码，
and the one token at a time,
一次一个 token ，
you just do n tokens at a time
你一次做 n 个 token ，
and then if it's fixed
然后如果它是固定的，
and you just need 196 by n steps,
你需要 196 x n 步，
the idea is that,
我们的想法是，
if you use high confidence tokens,
如果你使用高置信度 token ，
then they are potentially conditionally independent of each other at each step,
那么它们在每一步都可能是有条件的相互独立的，
and we can each of them can be predicted without affecting the other,
我们可以，预测它们中的每一个，而不会影响另一个，
so that seems to hold up.
所以，这似乎是站得住脚的。
Interesting.
有意思。
So the prompt is allowing you to navigate the latent space of the image itself,
提示允许你导航图像本身的潜在空间，
have you done any analysis or looked at
你有没有做过任何分析或看过，
what is the relationship between the prompting and the directions
提示与方向的关系，
or velocity or any other sort of metric,
或者速度或任何其他指标，
that you can look at in that latent representation exploration.
你可以在潜在表征探索中看到的。
Yeah, it's a good question,
是的，这是个好问题，
we haven't yet done a very thorough investigation,
我们还没有进行非常彻底的调查，
what we looked at was,
我们看到的是，
and I don't have it here,
我这里没有，
but we looked at some cross attention maps
但我们看到了交叉注意映射，
between the text embeddings and the and the image, the generated image,
在文本嵌入和生成图像之间，
and what you can see is that,
你可以看到的是，
you know, the, it does what you might expect,
它做的是你可能会想到的，
which is that there's cross-attension between the different nouns and the objects in the image,
那就是不同的名词和图像中的物体之间存在交叉注意，
when you have a verb that connects two objects,
当你有一个动词连接两个宾语时，
it seems to then highlight both those objects,
它似乎会突出显示这两个宾语，
sort of paying attention to that,
有点像是在注意这一点，
so that's one level of exploration,
所以这是一个层面的探索，
but I think we need to do more about,
但我认为我们需要做更多的（工作），
like as we walk around in latent space, what's the resulting image,
如果我们在潜在空间里走来走去，结果是什么图像，
if we move between two text prompts, what happens,
如果我们在两个文本提示之间移动，会发生什么，
we don't know yet,
我们还不知道，
the latent space smooth or it has abrupt jumps,
潜在空间平坦或有突变，
the editing suggests some smoothness here,
编辑表明这里有一些[流畅]，
as you iterate,
随着你的迭代，
but this is with a fixed prompt,
但这是一个固定的提示，
not with the changing prompt,
而不是不断变化的提示，
so I think we need to do more.
所以我认为我们需要做更多的工作。
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
Yeah, I had a question about like the cardinality portion of the results,
是的，我对结果的基数部分有个问题，
like one of the failure cases show that,
其中一个失败案例表明，
like the model can't really handle,
模型不能处理，
if you give it more than like six or seven of the same item,
如果给它超过六到七件相同的物品，
but sometimes when you don't specify anything in the prompt,
但有时，当你没有在提示符中指定任何内容时，
it automatically generates like more than that of the number of items,
它会自动生成比项目数更多的内容，
do you know why it breaks down,
你知道为什么会破坏，
when you give it like six or seven or eight.
当你给六、七或八个。
I think, it's my feeling,
我想，这是我的感觉，
and again, we haven't analyzed this is that,
再说一次，我们没有分析，
it's just that fewer small numbers are more common in the data.
这只是因为数据中更小的数字更常见。
Ah, gotcha.
啊，明白了。
You know, most images would just have a few, two, three, four,
大多数图像只会有几个，两个，三个，四个，
and then the model has just never seen ten or twenty,
然后模型就从来没有见过十或二十，
and then there's also not the way we train it,
还有，我们训练它的方式也不一样，
there's not this concept of graceful degradation from ten to many,
不存在优雅地从十个退化到许多的概念，
where might just say, okay, a crowd of people
可能只会说，好的，一群人，
and then you generate what looks like thirty people,
然后你产生比如三十个人，
I think we need more,
我想我们需要更多，
there have been papers that are trying to overcome this problem,
已经有一些论文试图解决这个问题，
I think explicitly through just enriching the data,
我认为，仅仅通过丰富数据就可以了，
I think more clever solutions are needed.
我认为还需要更聪明的解决方案。
When you do not specify a background of a request,
当你未指定请求的背景时，
how does it happen that,
为什么它，
is there a limited amount of backgrounds that it has to choose from randomly,
是否必须随机选择有限数量的背景，
or is there some sort of a generator,
或者有没有一种生成器，
that just how does it work,
它是如何工作的，
when you do not specify the background, for example, at all.
当你完全不指定背景时。
Yeah, it's a great question,
是的，这是个很好的问题，
so one thing we did was
所以我们做的一件事是，
just type in nonsense into the text prompt
在文本提示符中输入无意义的话，
and see what happens,
然后看看会发生什么，
and it seems to generate just random scenes,
它似乎只会生成随机的场景，
like of of, you know, mountains and the beach and so on,
比如山和海滩等等，
it doesn't generate nonsense,
它不会产生无意义的图，
so we think that the code book in the latent space is dominated by these kinds of backgrounds,
所以，我们认为潜在空间中的[编码本]是由这类背景主导的，
and somehow that what gets fed in, when you go through the decoder,
不知何故，当你通过解码器时，这些东西就会被输入，
so, yeah, I don't have a better answer than that.
所以，是的，我没有比这更好的答案了。
Hi, thanks for the talk,
嗨，谢谢你的演讲，
I kind of the mask-free in painting super interesting,
我认为无遮罩的画画非常有趣，
a lot of the prompts you showed had,
你展示的很多提示都有，
like the the correction was a small change from,
正确性有一点改变，
maybe the next slide,
可能是下一张，
I think one more, sorry,
我想更多一个，抱歉，
I'm looking for the one with the dog with the football in his mouth.
我在找那个嘴里叼着橄榄球的狗。
Yeah, many of these are kind of small changes from what's in there, right,
是的，其中许多都是与里面的东西不同的小变化，
you're going like give it the input as a basket with apples in it
给它一个装着苹果的篮子来输入，
and you're saying oranges,
而你说的是橘子，
have you tried,
你有没有试过，
if the like editing text is completely different,
如果比如编辑文本是完全不同的，
like you go from dog with a basketball to a cat bowling
比如从一只带着篮球的狗变成了一只猫带着保龄球，
or something like that?
或类似的东西？
Yep, there even something crazy,
是的，甚至有一些疯狂的东西，
like a city.
比如一座城市。
That doesn't work,
这不管用，
so we've tried that,
我们已经试过了，
it doesn't,
它不是，
so I think something like the instruct [pickics] to pickics,
我觉得像指示[]，
that it works for that,
它是管用的，
because they explicitly train it with large edits,
因为他们明确地用大编辑来训练它，
part of the problem could be the way we do the editing,
部分问题可能是我们进行编辑的方式，
which is based on these small backdrop steps,
这是基于这些小的背景步骤，
which just allow you to do local changes,
只允许你进行本地更改，
so we don't know if it's a limitation of the model
所以我们不知道这是模型的限制，
or a limitation of the gradient,
还是梯度的限制，
the SGD steps we do when we're doing the editing,
我们在编辑时所做的 SGD 步骤，
so what happens with the editing is start with the original image,
所以，编辑过程是从原始图像开始，
then take the text prompt
然后接受文本提示，
and just keep back propping
然后一直回溯，
till you know, it settles down converges,
直到它会稳定下来[聚合]，
say hundred steps,
比方说一百步，
and so each of those steps like I showed here is small changes,
所以像我在这里展示的每一个步骤都是很小的变化，
and if you want something like what you describe,
如果你想要像你描述的那样，
you need to have the ability to kind of jump faster through hundred steps,
你需要有在一百步中跳得更快的能力，
maybe if you did it for a million steps,
也许如果你走了一百万步，
you could have that change,
你就会有这样的改变，
we haven't yet looked at that.
我们还没有看到这一点。
Yeah, it's almost hard to imagine even what that middle ground would look like.
是的，几乎很难想象这种中间场景会是什么样子。
Yes, like do you have to pass through some valley of unrealistic images
是的，比如，你必须穿过一些不切实际的图像，
to get to this very large change,
才能到达这里的巨大变化，
here, each of those sub steps look like believable things,
这些步骤中的每一个看起来都是可信的，
so it could be an optimization problem.
所以这可能是一个最优化问题。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Maybe extension on that same question,
也许延伸同样的问题，
I'm curious for the case,
我很好奇这种情况，
where the not the entire image is changing,
不是整个图像都在变化，
but maybe at the image level you're changing, like the style, for example,
但可能是在图像层面上，比如风格，
like the main content is maintained,
比如主要内容保持不变，
but the style is being changed and modified,
但风格在改变和修改，
is that, have you tried these type of things before?
你以前尝试过这种类型的东西吗？
Ah, yes, I think so,
啊，是的，我想是的，
like, I don't have example,
比如，我没有这样的例子，
maybe something like this,
也许是这样的，
I think, it seems much harder to do realistic pause changes like the kinds,
我想，像这样做现实的停顿改变似乎要困难得多，
he was asking about compared to these global style changes,
他问的是与这些全局风格的变化相比，
because I think the global style
因为我认为全局风格可能
is controlled by maybe one or two elements of the code book or something like that,
由编码本的一两个元素或类似的东西控制，
whereas to to change pose or make drastic,
要改变姿势或进行剧烈的，
geometry changes might require much more interaction among the different tokens.
几何变化可能需要不同 token 之间更多的交互。
Hi, thank you for that great talk,
嗨，谢谢你的精彩演讲，
I was wondering, how does the model determine which picture is more accurate to the description
我想知道，模型如何确定哪张图片更符合描述，
or which is which has a better resolution,
或者哪张图片的分辨率更高，
part of the model determines that,
模型的一部分决定了这一点，
without needing to, needing the human oversight.
而不需要人类的监督。
So it doesn't, in practice,
所以在实践中并不是这样，
well, are you talking about training or inference?
你是在说训练还是推理？
Ah, with the inference.
啊，推理。
So we what we do is just use random seeds and generate a whole bunch of images
我们所做的就是使用随机的种子，生成一大堆图像，
and then we just pick out the one we like,
然后我们挑选出我们喜欢的一个，
so often what happens is that,
经常发生的情况是，
if you have 8 images or 16,
如果你有 8 张或 16 张图片，
3 or 4 of them would be really nice
其中 3 或 4 张会很好，
and then a few of them would look really bad,
但有几张看起来会很糟糕，
and we still don't have a self correcting way or automated way
我们仍然没有一种自我纠正的方式或自动的方式，
to say this image matches the prompt better.
来说这张图片更符合提示。
So, yeah, so so,
所以，是的，所以，
so in general, the hope is that,
所以，总的来说，希望的是，
the latent space has been trained in a sensible way,
潜在的空间已经以一种合理的方式进行了训练，
so that it will generate plausible images,
这样它就会产生可信的图像，
but, for example, you might generate a cat with, you know, the legs all in the wrong position
但是，例如，你可能会产生一只猫，腿都在错误的位置，
and then it's still using the right elements of the code book,
然后，它仍在使用编码本中正确的元素，
but it arranged them wrongly,
但排列错误，
so we do see those kinds of mistakes.
所以，我们确实看到了这类错误。
Okay, so for your next step in improving the resolution, you imagine,
好的，那么，对于你想的提高分辨率的下一步，
you'd go about it the same way?
你会以同样的方式去做吗？
Yeah, yeah, we'd have to somehow fix those issues.
是的，我们必须设法解决这些问题。
Okay, one more question.
好了，还有一个问题。
So I kind of have two questions in one,
我有两个问题，
so my first question is,
我的第一个问题是，
I'm not sure what are the limitations on the size of the corpus for the text and for the images,
我不确定文本和图像语料库的大小限制是什么，
but say, there's like a new or just that hasn't come out yet
但比如说，有一个新的但是还没有出来，
or like will in the next two months,
或者在接下来的两个月里，
if I were to ask in the prompt say,
如果我在提示符中问，
I want you to draw this in the style of this thing that isn't invented yet,
我想让你用这个还没有发明的东西的风格来画这个，
how would the model react to that change,
这个模型会对这种变化有什么反应，
and a separate question is,
另外，一个单独的问题是，
with these, especially the example with the masked images,
关于这些，特别是带有遮罩图像的示例，
the top row in the bottom row,
上面一行到下面一行，
how much new information are we actually getting from these images that the model spits out.
我们从这些模型给出的图像中获得了多少新信息。
So it's, it's a great, great question,
所以，这是一个非常好的问题，
so for the, for the data,
所以对于数据来说，
clearly the data is biased towards famous artists
很明显，数据偏向于著名艺术家，
and that's why we can say things like, you know, in the style of Rembrandt or Monet,
这就是为什么我们可以说伦勃朗或莫奈的风格，
and it has seen many examples of those,
它已经看到了许多这样的例子，
because this is data scraped from the web,
因为这是从网络上收集的数据，
if you had a new, the style of a new artist,
如果你有一个新艺术家的风格，
the only current way to do it would be through fine tuning,
目前唯一的方法是通过微调，
where we take those images of the person pair it with some text
我们将这些人的图像将其与一些文本配对，
and then kind of train the model to generate that,
然后对模型进行训练来生成，
this is kind of what the Dreambooth approach tries to do,
这就是 Dreambooth 方法试图做到的，
although that's specific to, you know, objects rather than the style,
尽管这是特定的对象，而不是风格，
but you could imagine using something like this
但你可以想象用这样的东西，
for the style of a new artist.
对于一位新艺术家的风格。
It's not yet zero shot,
这不是零次学习的，
where you just present these examples and say,
你只是展示这些例子，然后说，
can you generate something based on this text prompt, but in that style,
你能根据这个文本提示生成一些东西，但以那种风格，
so that's something we would like to work towards.
所以，这是我们愿意努力的方向。
Regarding the masking, I didn't fully follow the question,
关于遮罩，我没有完全理解问题，
so you said something about the top and bottom rows.
所以你说了一些关于上面和下面的事情。
Yeah, I think it was one of the slides way past this one,
是的，我认为这是其中一张幻灯片，
but it was a pretty general question,
但这是一个非常普遍的问题，
it was, how much new information are we actually gaining from these,
它是我们从这些图片中获得了多少新信息，
I guess pictures that haven't, like no one has seen before,
我想还没有人见过的图片，
like with the bear on the bicycle.
比如骑自行车的熊一样。
Oh, you mean are you talking about memorization versus like, is it actually is,
哦，你是说你是在说记忆和它实际的样子，
do you mean, if this is already in the dataset, the training dataset?
你的意思是，如果这已经在训练数据集中？
Um, yeah.
嗯，是的。
Yeah, so this is actually a great question,
嗯，这是一个很好的问题，
and I think, I don't think we still have very good answers to this,
我认为我们对这个问题仍然没有很好的答案，
you know, is it is a large language model,
这是一个大型语言模型，
just hallucinating something seen before,
只是出现了以前见过的幻觉，
just mix and match,
只要混合搭配，
probably, it's probably this is also doing something like that,
它可能也在做类似的事情，
where it's seen bears before and bikes
它以前见过熊和自行车，
and has been able to put them together in a plausible way,
已经能够以一种可信的方式将它们结合在一起，
it's unlikely that the exact same image was in the dataset,
数据集中不太可能有完全相同的图像，
but again, we don't have really good tools yet to go,
但同样，我们没有好的工具，
like, like we could try to search based on some kind of embedding CLIP embedding or something
我们可以尝试搜索嵌入 CLIP 或其他，
to look for similar images,
以寻找相似的图像，
but at the scale at which we are training hundreds of millions of images,
但是在我们训练数以亿计的图像的规模上，
we haven't actually gone in and look
我们还没有去看，
to see how much his memorization was,
看看它的记忆力有多强，
new combination of concepts,
新概念的结合，
I do think it's the latter,
我认为是后者，
because it seems unlikely that,
因为这似乎不太可能，
you know, these kinds of images would be in the training dataset.
这些类型的图像会在训练数据集中。
Okay, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
Let's give Dilip one more round of applause.
让我们再给 Dilip 更多掌声。